Geoffrey Bergeret French Nationality 27 years old

DevOps Engineer

« Divide and Rule »

+44 7871 334653 job@gbergeret.com www.gbergeret.org

Profile

By experience, I acquired lots of skills in several area like: *Software*, *System*, *Network* or *DevOps* Culture. Now my goal is to focus on the DevOps way: "*Develop your infrastructure as code and automate everything to make it smarter*".

Work Experience

DevOps Engineer at Fluidly – 01/2019 to now

- Restructured Terraform projects integrate them with the CI/CD pipeline.
- And much more to come...

DevOps Engineer at Onfido – 10/2017 to 01/2019

- Initiated GitOps principales from Infrastructure as Code (with Peer Review).
- Implement Jenkins Pipeline integration with terraform to run terraform from Jenkins.
- Restructured Terraform projects integrate them with the CI/CD pipeline.
- Integrate Ansible with our Terraform projects to manage OS provisioning.
- Worked on AWS accounts segregation with AWS Organisation (workload segregation).
- Deployed gravitational teleport as SSH bastion.
- Deployed and maintain transit VPC (with datapath.io solution) cross regions and VPCs.

DevOps Engineer at Drivetribe – 11/2016 to 10/2017

- Infrastructure as Code with terraform and ansible (GitOps).
- Move platform to docker infrastructure with Kubernetes as container scheduler.
- Refactoring environments to be easy to run, update and dispose (qa, staging, prod).
- Work around failure points and scalability to be online as much as possible..
- Improve, speed up and stabilise the releasing process.

DevOps Engineer at Onfido – 04/2016 to 11/2016

- Move to infrastructure as Code with terraform and ansible (all in git).
- Move platform to micro-services infrastructure with Kubernetes as container scheduler.
- Work around failure points to be as much as possible always online.

System and DevOps Engineer at Contentment – 10/2015 to 03/2016

- In charge of all System and DevOps part, sizing the infrastructure and support it.
- Migrate and automate the deployment of the existing architecture in AWS with Docker.

Education & Training

2015: Master of Science in Computer and Network Engineering (1st class) at ESIPE

Languages Skills

French -> Native

English —> Fluent (living in UK from 2015)

Technical Skills

DevOps: Kubernetes, terraform, test-kitchen, GitOps, CI/CD (Jenkins)

System: Linux, Bash, Ansible, Python, Docker

Infrastructure: AWS, VPN, Kubernetes, Proxmox, Firewall (pfsense, ipables)

Networking: Routing (OSPF, BGP), VRRP, OpenVPN, DHCP, DNS **Database**: MERISE, ORM, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB **Software Developpement**: UML, Java, C/C++, Jekyll (Liquid), Git

Management Skills

Project Management Independent

Team organisation Facilitate meeting

Conduct training Seminar facilitator

Hobbies

Board Games Economy/Finance Cooking
Jogging/Fitness

Traveling Motorcycle